When men ruled as gods, one was chosen to change the world.
Exodus: Gods and Kings is a adventure, drama,
action film directed by Ridley Scott.
The defiant leader Moses rises up against the Egyptian Pharaoh Ramses, setting 400,000 slaves on a
monumental journey of escape from Egypt and its terrifying cycle of deadly plagues.
Moses, played by Christian Bale.
Ramses II, played by Joel Edgerton.
Nun, played by Ben Kingsley.
Sethos I, played by John Turturro.
Joshua, played by Aaron Paul.
Nefertari, played by Golshifteh Farahani.
Exodus: Gods and Kings is a 2014 biblical epic film directed and produced by Ridley Scott,
and written by Adam Cooper, Bill Collage, Jeffrey Caine, and Steven Zaillian.
The film stars Christian Bale, Joel Edgerton, John Turturro, Aaron
Paul, Ben Mendelsohn, Sigourney Weaver, and Ben Kingsley.
It is inspired by the biblical episode of the Exodus of the Hebrews from
Egypt led by Moses and related in the Book of Exodus.
Development on the film was first announced by Scott in June 2012.
Filming occurred primarily in Spain beginning in October 2013, with
additional filming at Pinewood Studios in England.
The film was released on December 12, 2014, by
20th Century Fox, to mixed reviews.
Critics praised the visual effects and cast performances, but criticized its pacing,
screenplay, lack of emotional heft, and inaccuracy to the source material.
The film also received accusations of whitewashing for its primarily Caucasian cast, and was
banned in Egypt and in the United Arab Emirates for "historical inaccuracies".
It was considered a financial disappointment, earning $268
million worldwide on a budget of $140–200 million.
The film explores themes of moses, bible, racism, slave, ancient egypt.
The tone is emotional.